<?xml version="1.0"?>
<book>
	<bookinfo>
		<title>LuaJ - Scripting Engine Shell</title>
		<author>
			<firstname>Zigmantas</firstname><surname>Kry&#382;ius</surname>
		</author>
	</bookinfo>
	<chapter id="overview"><title>Overview</title>
		<para>
			To use the plugin, first start it from Plugins menu or open up the Console
			dockable and select the LuaJ-SE shell (LuaJ - Scripting Engine).
			Once selected, it will attempt to start up the Read-Eval-Print-Loop, and if successful,
			the LuaJ-SE prompt will be displayed. If not successful, the LuaJ plugin
			may need to be configured. Refer to that plugin's documentation for information
			on how to configure it.
		</para>
		<para>
		The LuaJ-SE Shell plugin adds to jEdit the LuaJ script handler so you
		can write macros and startup scripts in LuaJ. The console interface to the LuaJ script
		engine shell can be useful for creating and testing jEdit macros in LuaJ.
		</para>
	</chapter>
	<chapter id="actions"><title>Evaluating Code</title>
		<para>
			The easiest way to evaluate code in the shell is to simply type it in and hit enter.
			There are several actions available that make it easier to test a portion of your
			code without having to manually copy and paste it.
		</para>
		<para>
			These actions can be found in the menu Plugins -> LuaJ-SE Shell. Using these actions, you can
			use the shell to evaluate the active buffer, any selected text within that buffer,
			or an external LuaJ script.
		</para>
		<para>
			Any variables or functions defined in the shell will persist until the loop is
			terminated.
			<!-- manually stopped and restarted. -->
		</para>
	</chapter>
	<!--
	<chapter id="stop-restart"><title>Stopping and Restarting</title>
		<para>
			To stop the loop, click on the Stop button in the Console dockable. After it's stopped,
			hit Enter to start it back up again. Restarting can be used to reset the environment,
			or you can simply stop the loop to conserve system resources.
		</para>
	-->
	<chapter id="global-variables"><title>Global Variables</title>
		<para>
		LuaJ-SE Shell Plugin provides the same global variables as the JavaScriptShell Plugin.
		<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		<emphasis>view</emphasis> - the current jEdit view
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		<emphasis>editPane</emphasis> - the current jEdit editPane
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		<emphasis>textArea</emphasis> - the current jEdit textArea
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		<emphasis>buffer</emphasis> - the current jEdit buffer
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		<emphasis>wm</emphasis> - the dockableWindowManager of the curre
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		<emphasis>scriptPath</emphasis> - the path of the script in the current buffer
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		<emphasis>console</emphasis> - console
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		<emphasis>output</emphasis> - output
		</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		<para>
		<emphasis>engine</emphasis> - LuaJ scripting engine
		</para>
		</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</chapter>
	<chapter id="macros-scripts"><title>Macros and Scripting</title>
		<para>
			jEdit macros in LuaJ are LuaJ scripts with file name extension <emphasis>lua</emphasis>, placed in the jEdit's settings
			or home subdirectory <emphasis>/macros</emphasis>. Macros are visible in the <emphasis>Macros</emphasis> menu when LuaJ-SE Shell
			plugin is started and macros are <emphasis>rescanned</emphasis> (in <emphasis>Macros</emphasis> menu).
		</para>
		<para>
			The following code can be saved as a sample macro in LuaJ:
			<programlisting>
	view:splitHorizontally()
			</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>
		After the LuaJ-SE Shell plugin is started, via the plugin's menu item
		<emphasis>Load startup script(s)</emphasis> one can load so-called start-up script(s)
		where some handy functions are collected.
		</para>
	</chapter>
	<chapter id="contacts"><title>Contacts</title>
		<para>
			Author's contact: <email id="email">zigmas.kr@gmail.com</email>.
		</para>
	</chapter>
</book>
